(ｴﾙ)人を正して
お母さんを取り戻す…｡➡
I will correct mankind and take back my mother.
That is my duty.
それが 僕の使命…｡
(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)うりゃあ～！ はあっ！
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)神は この戦争に
お前の子供を利用するだろう｡
The gods will likely use your child in this war.
If your child joins them, he will die as well.
戦えば お前の子供も死ぬ｡
Stop it. Don't pick on Jeanne.
やめろ！
ジャンヌさんをいじめるな！
You haven't changed.
変わらないな お前は｡
What? What do you know!
何！ なんなのよ！
Would you dance with me again?
また踊ってくれるか？
はっ…｡
≫(看守)はぁ はぁ はぁ…｡
≫タッタッタッ(足音)
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)助かった 感謝する｡
You have my thanks.
I never would've imagined you'd be
with the saint.
(ﾘﾀ)まさか 聖女様が一緒だとは
思わなかったわ｡
I am no longer a saint.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)もう聖女ではない｡
Rita, you always show up
right when I need you!
リタって いつも
ピンチなときに来てくれるね｡
≫ピィーッ！ ピィーッ！(笛の音)
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)急ごう｡
Let us hurry!
Rage of Bahamut
In the past,
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)過去
我々と人間の関係は良好でした｡➡
we had a favorable relationship with mankind.
１０年前の
バハムートによる悲劇の際は➡
During the Bahamut catastrophe
10 years ago,
互いに手を取り
多大な犠牲を払って➡
we took each other by the hand,
and made heavy sacrifices
この世界を守り抜きました｡➡
to successfully defend the world
from oblivion.
にもかかわらず 人間たちは
信仰心を失い 神の不要を説き➡
But despite this,
mankind lost its way
claiming it no longer needed the gods.
Men attacked our shrines,
挙句の果てに 我々の神殿を襲い
神を殺害するまでに至りました｡➡
and even dared to kill
our brothers and sisters.
彼らが 自らの過ちに気付くまで
我々は この横暴に➡
Should we simply suffer this oppression in silence
until mankind realizes its mistake?
静かに
耐え続けるべきなのでしょうか？➡
I say no.
否｡ これ以上 人間たちの横暴を
許すことはできません｡
We can no longer forgive mankind's
domineering ways.
We must admonish those
who have wronged us.
神々を侮辱した者たちに➡
我々の力を
思い知らせてやるのです｡
殺された同胞の無念を晴らし
世界の秩序を取り戻すのです｡
We must avenge our fallen comrades
and restore balance to the world.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)ガブリエル様
エルの力は まだ未知数です｡➡
Gabriel.
El's powers are still unknown.
このような戦に
果たして耐えられるか…｡
Can he withstand this war?
There is no need to worry.
心配には及びません｡
エルが 人の力を封印したのは➡
El has shown to be capable of
何度も証明されています｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)ですが…｡➡
stripping the humans of their powers
on multiple occasions. But...
やるしかないのです｡
We have no other choice.
(指揮官)空挺隊 行け！ 行け～！
Air brigade! Go, go!
(指揮官)
地上兵は 投擲車両の準備をせよ！
Ground forces, prepare the ballistic weapons!
(指揮官)
兵の数を正面に集中させろ！
Concentrate our forces to the front!
(指揮官)
ゴーレムの配置を急がせろ！
Get the golems in position!
(一同)シャリオスは死ね～！➡
Charioce shall die!
王宮の兵は全滅しろ～！
The royal capital's soldiers shall be defeated!
(肉屋の妻)ほんとに 戦争するなら
よそでやってほしいね｡
If they're going to make war,
I'd wish they'd do it somewhere else!
(肉屋の主人)
うるせぇ！ とっとと逃げねぇと➡
Shut up! We gotta get out of here
before all hell breaks loose!
戦が始まっちまうぞ！
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)この戦で
俺たちの真価が問われますね｡
This battle will give us the chance
to prove our worth.
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)神と戦うことに
お前は 何も感じないのか？
Does fighting the gods
not give you any pause?
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)
えっ？ だったら何なんすか？
What? What about it?
ったく カイザル団長みたいなこと
言わないでくださいよ｡➡
Honestly, please don't go all
Captain Kaisar on me.
宣戦布告してきたのは
神なんですから➡
The gods are the ones who declared war on us.
やるっきゃないでしょ｡ ん？➡
We can't back down now.
Thanks, you guys.
おお～ お前ら ご苦労｡➡
Do a good job guarding our flanks, okay?
後方支援 しっかりやれよ～｡
(ﾌﾞｴﾙ)俺たちが前線だ｡
はあ？
We'll be the ones on the front lines.
What?
(ﾌﾞｴﾙ)
人間様は 安全な所で見物してろ｡
You precious humans
can watch us from safety.
なんだと!?
What did you say?
(ﾌﾞｴﾙ)グルル…｡
うっ｡
(ﾌﾞｴﾙ)
お前たちの王が決めたことだ｡
It's what your king decided.
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)
な な… 何なんすか あの態度｡➡
What was with his attitude?
Dias, teach him some manners!
ディアスさん
やっちゃってくださいよ！
(看守)こっちだ！
This way!
ふんっ んっ んん～ んっ！ あっ｡
うげっ…｡
Through here!
(ﾘﾀ)こっち｡
≫(看守)撃て 撃て～！ 撃て～！
Fire! Fire!
Fire!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)うっ！
ジャンヌさん！
Jeanne!
こんにゃろ～！
Why you little...!
ゴン！
(一同)うわっ ああ～！
(ﾘﾀ)ニーナ！
Nina!
ここで足止めしとくから
先に行って｡
You go on ahead, I'll hold them off here!
(ﾘﾀ)大丈夫？
すぐ追いつける｡
Will you be okay?
Don't worry, it won't take me long
to catch up to you. I'm fast.
私 足速いから｡
Let's go.
(ﾘﾀ)行きましょう｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)むちゃはするな｡
Be careful!
しゃあ～ こいや！
All right! Bring it on!
これ以上行くと
ニーナが分からなくなっちゃうわ｡
If we go any further,
Nina won't know which direction to take.
ドォーン！
ええっ!?
撃て～！
シュン シュン シュン…
Fire!
うわっ おお～！
ドカン！
ドカーン！
カチャン(ﾌﾞﾚｰｷが外れる音)
ええっ… ええっ!? な… 何？
な な… 何～!?
リタ～！ ジャンヌさ～ん！
Rita!
Jeanne!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ ﾘﾀ)あっ｡
(看守たち)ああっ！
グッドタイミングでしょ？
二人とも大丈夫？
Good timing, right?
You guys okay?
(ﾘﾀ)これ このまま走り続けると
どこに行くのかしら？
I wonder where this leads to.
I do not know.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)分からない｡
私も ここまで来たことはない｡
I have never been this far either.
(ﾘﾀ)ニーナ！
Nina!
ふぅ…｡
(ﾘﾀ)ちょっと 何踊ってんのよ｡
What are you dancing for?
あっ いや…｡
Well...
(回想)((また踊ってくれるか？))
Would you dance with me again?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ニーナ！
ニーナ ブレーキ！
-Nina!
-Nina, the brake!
は… はい！ これ？
Okay! This?
キィー…
キキィー！
ぬぅ～！
ボキッ！
ああっ う… うそ～！
Oh, no!
Everyone, hold on tight!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)
みんな しっかりつかまっていろ！
うわっ ぎゃあ～～！
ドォーン！
ケガはないかしら？
Is anyone hurt?
ああ 私は大丈夫だ｡ ニーナは？
No, I am fine.
What about Nina?
≫ほえぇ～…｡
(２人)あっ｡
死んだかと思った｡
I thought I was dead.
(看守)
おい！ そこで何をしている!?
Hey!
What are you doing there?
Men?
男？
はあっ！
≫(囚人たち)おお～！
What the hell is all that racket?
なんだよ うるせぇな｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)何かあったのか？
Has something happened?
≫(看守)待て！
≫(看守)おい 待て！
-Stop right there!
-Get back here!
(看守)待ちやがれって言ってるだろ｡
あいつら…｡
Those crazy...
なんで私たち
応援されてるんですかね？
Why do you think they're cheering us on?
(ﾘﾀ)へっ？
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)さあな｡
-What?
-I don't know!
Rage of Bahamut
(重臣たち)おぉ…｡
(重臣)なんだ？
So they've come.
来たか｡
あれ見ろ！
Look up there!
攻撃を開始せよ｡
Commence the attack.
El.
エル｡
ドォーン！
Protect His Majesty!
(兵士)陛下を守れ！
ドカーン！
ちょ… ちょっと
神 強すぎないっすか？
Time-out.
Aren't these gods way too strong?
This light is stripping us of our power.
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)この光が
人の力を封印しているのだ｡
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)漆黒兵部隊は
何やってんすかね？
What are the Onyx Soldiers doing?
こんなん相手にするの
ヤツら 得意じゃないっすか？
I thought handling this type of enemy
is their specialty!
Even they are no match to this light.
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)ヤツらでも
あの光には かなうまい｡
だから逃げたんすか｡
Is that why they ran?
≪シュン シュン シュン…
(兵士たち)うわっ ああっ｡
Your Highness, they have broken through
the castle gates.
(上級兵)申し上げます｡
城門を突破されました｡➡
It will not be long before they are at the castle.
間もなく 城に来ます｡
(重臣たち)あぁ…｡
あれを使う｡
(重臣たち)あっ…｡
We will use the device.
お言葉ながら 陛下
あれは 開発途上であります｡
Forgive me, Your Highness,
but the device is still in development!
今使えば 陛下に
どのような事態が起きるか➡
If it is used now, there is no telling what
it might do or what danger it may put you in.
読めませぬ｡
I did not ask for your opinion.
お前の意見は聞いていない｡
I told you to get it ready.
用意しろと言っている｡
あっ… ただいま｡
At once, Your Highness!
All right, I guess we should get going too.
さて 俺らも そろそろ行くか｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)あっ？
-Kaisar, take off your iron hand.
-Why?
カイザル 義手を外せ｡
なぜだ？
Just hurry up and do it.
早くしろ｡
Once you take it off,
fasten it to the lock.
外したら錠に固定しろ｡
Stretch out the thumb first,
まずは親指を伸ばせ｡ 次に中指だ｡
then the middle finger.
一体 何をする気だ？
何って ここから逃げ出すんだよ！
What are you planning on doing?
What do you mean?
We're escaping of course.
次は親指を曲げて
人さし指と小指を伸ばせ｡
Next, bend the thumb and stretch out
the index and pinkie fingers.
All right, now, get as far away from it
as you can!
よし！
そこから できるだけ離れろ！
あっ｡
(看守)おい！ 何をしている!?
Hey! What are you doing?
Hurry! Hurry up and step back!
早く！ 早くしろ！
くっ｡
パディオシュプロースティナズｨカ
カティドーレ！
ドカン！
(看守)うっ！
なんて顔してやがんの｡
Look at your face.
Don't worry, I'll make you a better one.
もっといいの作ってやっから➡
そこで のびてるヤツの鍵で➡
Could you grab that guy's keys
and unlock this cell for me?
こっちの扉も開けてくれねぇか！
ふふふん｡
I'd like my next hand to be
one that won't explode.
次の義手は爆発しないのを頼む｡
へへっ｡
That wasn't me, Rita was the one who built that in
because she was worried about you.
ありゃ俺じゃなくて
リタが仕込んだんだ➡
お前を心配してな｡
She was worried?
心配してって… 爆発しただろう！
It exploded!
Stop right there!
止まれ！
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ ﾌｧﾊﾞﾛ)んん～！
バキッ！
何？ 今の音｡
What was that sound?
あっ みんな いなくなっちゃった｡
Everyone's gone!
(ﾘﾀ)行くわよ｡
あっ…｡
Let's go.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)リタ！
Rita!
Lady Jeanne!
ジャンヌ様！
カイザル｡
Kaisar!
ええ～ すご～い！
Hey, wow!
What are you doing here?
You're a bit more developed now,
aren't you, Nina?
What are you looking at?
Lady Jeanne,
I'm glad to see you safe.
Kaisar,
I am glad to see you as well.
Hello?
You guys know we don't
have time for this, right?
What is that?
Oh, crap!
It's okay, it's okay
I cast the usual spell
Stagnation, stagnation
My words and heart are at odds
Default
I've taken all the paint
なんでいるの？ やった～！
And mixed up all the colors
Until you're left with me
ふん｡ ちったぁ女らしくなったか？
ニーナ｡
ふっ！
ぐっ！ ああ～ いってぇ｡
So fragile
Yet strong
何見てんの？
Close to overflowing
But not spilling
ジャンヌ様 よくぞ ご無事で｡
Because I'm incomplete
I won't amount to much
カイザル そなたこそ｡
This is just a good luck charm
I'm not asking for your help
I was just clinging to you
あなたたち そんなこと
やってる場合じゃないんだけど｡
Let's end it all today
あっ！
うう～ な… 何？ これ｡
I'm done living this pointless life
Let's end it all today
やべぇ！
I've taken my last, pointless breath
To whom it may concern, see ya and goodbye
I killed the person I was yesterday
(ﾘﾀ)わあ～！
ええ～!?
A new morning is coming
ドドォーン！
-Nina! Have you brushed up lately?
-Brushed up to the max!
ゴゴゴゴッ…(地響き)
パキッ パキッ
See? How about this? And that!
Oh, so you're talking about your skin...
ドドォーン！
Next time on Rage of Bahamut: Virgin Soul,
"A Farewell to Arms."
ドォーン！
Like shooting...
That was my bad.
ドドォーーン‼
No worries, Master.
Baha Soul...???
Baha Baha Baha Soul
Watch next time too!
Ba Baha Baha Baha Soul?